safetykart.com 2015-10-29

# Privacy & Security - SafetyKart

SafetyKart.com places your privacy first and foremost. This Privacy Policy provides you with the details in the manner your data is collected and used by us. You are advised to please read the Privacy Policy carefully.

At SafetyKart.com, we are extremely proud of our commitment to protect your privacy. We value your trust and put in time and effort to earn it. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our site.

  * Our privacy policy is subject to change without prior notice. Please review this policy periodically and keep up-to-date with the revised policy.
  * We hope to clearly inform that by visiting SafetyKart.com, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.
  * By mere use of the Website, you are consenting to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Policy set.

**Collection of Personal Information:**

As per policy, we only collect details that have been provided by you on Registration. We may collect additional information with reference to your participation in our promotions or competitions offered by us and information provided by you while giving feedback or while completing profile forms.

You can browse the Website without revealing your personal information. However, once you share your personal information with us, your identity will be known to us. We will indicate the fields that you are required to fill and the fields that are optional. You will be provided with the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular service or feature on the Website.   
**  
****Cookies:**

Data will be collected through "cookies" on certain pages of the Website to help analyse our web page flow, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. Certain features on our website will only be available through the use of "cookies".

We also use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can also help us provide information that is targeted to your interests. You always have the option to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the Website and you may be required to re-enter your password more frequently during a session.

Additionally, you may encounter "cookies" or other similar devices on certain pages of the Website that are placed by third parties. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties.

If you purchase from SafetyKart.com, we will collect information about your buying behaviour for remarketing. Also, we collect some additional information, such as a billing address and tracking information from cheques or money orders.

If you choose to post messages on our message boards, chat rooms or other message areas or leave feedback, we will collect that information you provide to us. We retain this information as necessary to resolve disputes, provide customer support and troubleshoot problems as permitted by law.

If you choose to correspond with us through emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Website, we may collect such information into a file specific to you.

We collect personally identifiable information (email address, name, phone number details, etc.) from you when you set up a free account with us. While you can browse some sections of our Website without being a registered member, certain activities (such as placing an order) do require registration. We do use your contact information to send you offers based on your previous orders and your interests.

 **Personally Identifiable Information:**

We may collect the following personally identifiable information about you:

  * First and Last name.
  * Mobile phone number and contact details.
  * ZIP/Postal code.

We use contact information internally to:

  * Direct our efforts for product improvement.
  * Contact you as for order fulfilment assistance.
  * Send you newsletter or promotional emails.

 **Use of Personal Information:**

We may use the personal information that you provide, for the services you request. We may use your personal information to market to you and will provide the option to opt-out of them. Your personal information will be used to resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; help promote a safe service; collect money; measure consumer interest in our products and services, inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, and updates; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; enforce our terms and conditions; and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

In our efforts to continually improve our product and service offerings, we will collect and analyse demographic and profile data about your activity on our Website.

We identify and use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Website. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information.

We will occasionally ask you to complete optional online surveys. These surveys may ask you for contact information and demographic information (like zip code, age, or  
income level). We use this data to tailor your experience at our Website, providing you with content that we think you might be interested in and to display content according to your preferences.

 **Security:**

We have appropriate technical and security measures in place to prevent unauthorised or unlawful access to, accidental loss of, destruction or damage to your information. When we collect data through the Site, we collect your only personal details on a secure server. Our servers are secured by firewalls. 

We **do not** collect **any** payment card details electronically. **You are strongly recommended not to send full credit or debit card details in unencrypted electronic communications with us.** We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of your information. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you. You are responsible for protecting unauthorised access to your password and computer.

 **Consent:**

By submitting data to us or our agent or using the Site, you consent to our use of your data in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy.

 **Copyright:**

The Privacy Policy presented above is copyrighted. Use by third parties, even by way of extract, for commercial purposes is not allowed. Infringements may be subject to legal action. This Privacy Policy can change at any time to include / exclude clauses and SafetyKart.com does not bear responsibility for updating Users on the same.

 **User’s Consent:**

Through the use of our Website and/ or by providing your information, you willingly consent to the collection and use of the information you disclose on the Website in accordance with the Privacy Policy, including but not limited to your consent for sharing your information as per this privacy policy.

If there is a change in our privacy policy, it will be posted on this page. We would suggest that you should revise it and stay aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

 **Issues of Grievance** **:  
**

In accordance with Information Technology Act 2000 and rules made there under, the contact details of the Grievance Officer are provided below:

**SafetyKart Retail Pvt. Ltd.**  
402, Mohan Tower, 1 Commercial Complex   
Wazirpur Industrial Area, New Delhi - 110052

Voice :  +91 11 45074706  
Email: [customer@safetykart.com](mailto:care@safetykart.com)   
Time: Mon - Friday (9:30 - 18:30) Sat (9:30 – 14:30)

 **  
Write to Us:**

We will address all questions regarding the above statements. Simply write to: [customer@safetykart.com](mailto:care@safetykart.com)
